# Mohammed Shafiq



Address:
Jubail, Saudi Arabia
Phone:
+966 571677340
+973 33963704
Email:
Shafiq2000us@gmail.com

# **Summary**

I am a product designer and UI/UX based mobile app developer, with almost 9 years of technical experience including delivering end to end UX/UI design for software products. I intend to work for an energetic and fun team to display and grow my abilities as a **Software Developer.** 

# **Skill Highlights**

- Android with Rest and MVVM
- Flutter development and design
- Problem solver
- Swift , Dart, Java, Kotlin
- Python, JavaScript beginner
- Figma Prototyping
- Unit testing

- iOS Development
- Java Programming
- Social media Management
- Oracle 11g express, SQLite
- Adobe Photoshop and illustartor
- UX/UI design
- Documentation

# **Experience**

## Android/IOS and flutter Trainer JUL 2020 - JUN 2021

TechGraylogix, Mangalore

- Android and IOS development training to college students and project guidance on computer based applications. Arduino based projects.
- Took interviews, selected candidates for staff.
- Built many small scale apps for students like TODO apps, Weather Apps, and Piano Apps. All on Flutter and Android.
- Also helped students build professional resume and portfolio with with Figma,
   Adobe photoshop and Corel draw.

## Mobile App UI/UX developer - JAN 2020-Current

Freelancer, Bahrain

- Worked as a freelancer for some time and built a grocery app called Frocery for a Mangalore company called Frocery. Integrated API's and built the front end with Android.
- Built an app for a cold store called *Tadbit Retail* in Bahrain to handle daily customer credits and vendor credits. Payments, reminders and account keeping were all handled offline via the mobile application.
- UI/UX design of a flutter application called *FarAway* for Tenants and landlords, facilitating maintenance services and rent payments.

#### Techno Sales- OCT 2019- NOV 2019

Fame Tech Solutions, Manama, Bahrain

- Worked for a short span of 2 months as a techno sales engineer.
- Learnt about the different modules of ERP.
- Took part in client meetings and sales pitches.
- Designed brochures for new product called E-menu. Also handled Business proposals and client presentations .

#### Founder - JUL 2018 - JAN 2019

Tadbit Creative, Manama Bahrain

- I founded a laser cutting company that manufactured decoratives and gifts.
- Managed Procurement of ICT equipments and industrial machines.
- Everything from designing, cutting, assembling, packaging, marketing, sales and delivery was handled single handedly.
- I also handled branding, Website, SEO, Social media Marketing, Logo Design and content management.

## Manager - JAN 2016 - DEC 2019

Talapady Market Wll, East Riffa, Bahrain

- Handled purchases, stocks, inventory, store, employee salaries, Lmra, Gosi, legal work like visa application and MOIC activities, Audits and vat related activities.
- Run a departmental store as a family commitment for more than 2 years.
- Learnt people management skills: Experience with managing bigger group of people and employee retention.

## App developer and Techno presales- AUG 2015 - JUL 2018

Cloud Alert Ventures, Bahrain

- Cloud Alert mobile app was built from scratch in Android and IOS.
- Tasks involved **UI design**, Embedability, White labeling & code maintenance, Documentaion, PreSales Presentation and pitching for clients like banks and government institutions.
- Travelling to "Payments and Gateways" exhibitions (Singapore, Dubai and Kenya) where we promoted and created awareness for the product.
- Handled travel logistics and PR related activities for all the exhibitions.

#### Java programmer /Product analyst - AUG 2013 - AUG 2015

Hexadimensional Corporation, Bahrain

- Deployment and Maintenance of SMS alert systems, bulk sms, SMPP gateway installation and integration.
- Internal java modules and apps development with Java swing and AWT libraries.
- Module based Djinne RDBMS Storage Layer Design and development for performance and efficiency tuning algorithms.
- Bulk sms desktop client called Hexapp.

## Embedded C Unit tester/ Developer - SEP 2009 - FEB 2013

Delphi Automotives, Bangalore, India

- We served clients like Peageot, Volvo, Chrysler and Daimler in developing and testing their EMS software.
- Tasks involved development in embedded C, testing, bug reporting and Peer reviews.
- Analyze data and create comprehensive reports.
- Interviewed and Recruited new staff for company.
- I was also a part of the Delphi "Fun at Work" Team.

Intern - JUL 2008 - JUN 2009

Kyocera Wireless, Bangalore, India

- Worked for a Japanese client for implementation of the Abstraction layer under LTE.
- Worked as junior programmer in development of a platform layer called SIAL.
- It was also part of the academic project. First hands on experience using C++ for data packetization.

#### **Education**

Bachelor of Engineering: EnC- 2003-2007

VTU Belgaum, P A College of Engineering, Mangalore

Masters in Science: **Embedded Systems** – 2007-2009

MAHE University, Manipal School Of Information Sciences, Manipal

# Languages

English, Hindi, Malayalam and Kannada

#### **Profile**

Passport Number K8085262 Citizenship Indian

Vaccination Status Pfizer 2 doses

Marital Status Married

**Bahrain** Visa Status RP valid till June 2022

**Saudi** Visa Status Multiple Entry Business Visa Valid till August 2022

Whatsapp 00966571677340, 0097333963704